Aaron,
am
I
high priest of
first
the
Israel.
a year
Once
once
only
where no other
went
I
permitted
man on earth was
go.
to
morning I
one
On that
aside my garments of
laid
glory.
gold and
with
body
I washed my
water,
plain
and I put on
linen,
white
servant,
like a
with nothing
man
like a
of.
boast
to
I walked toward
then
And
with my heart
veil
the
throat.
in my
that heavy curtain was
Behind
seat,
mercy
the
it,
above
and
cloud,
in the
of the living
presence
the
God.
in alone.
went
I
nation stood outside,
whole
The
its breath
holding
year,
and every
fell shut
curtain
as the
me,
behind
I
certain
I was not
out alive.
come
would
me
hear
You who
of my
two
I lost
sons.
own
and Abihu,
Nadab
boys,
my
before the
down
were struck
LORD,
fire
strange
for they offered
Him that He had
before
commanded.
not
even
And I was not
to mourn them:
allowed
bodies
my cousins carried their
camp,
out of the
I stood at the
while
of the tabernacle,
door
to rend my clothes
forbidden
my place.
leave
or
gave
LORD
So when the
concerning me,
warning
His
it
take
I did not
lightly;
it in my
heard
I
every time I reached
bones
veil.
for the
spoke it to
LORD
The
Moses,
brother
my
brought me the
Moses
and
word:
Aaron thy brother,
unto
Speak
not at
come
that he
holy
all times into the
before
place within the vail
seat,
mercy
the
the ark;
upon
which is
not:
die
that he
in
appear
for I will
the mercy
upon
the cloud
seat.
charge
That was my
veil
to stand at the
and not
people
for the
consumed.
be
me:
Understand
not bear their
did
I
guilt.
not;
could
I
blood
bring
I had to
sin before
own
for my
it for
brought
ever I
theirs.
carried the blood
only
I
in,
alive.
and came out
the LORD
law
For the
through Moses was plain,
gave
red through
ran
and it
I did:
everything
blood
for it is the
for
atonement
that maketh an
soul.
the
innocent had to die,
Something
of us could
none
or
near.
draw
you what
tell
Let me
with my own
did
I
hands,
year
for I did it
and could have
year
after
it in the dark.
done
me two goats
brought
They
offering,
sin
for the people's
of
law
and as the
commanded
Moses
lots over them:
cast
I
shall cast lots
Aaron
And
goats;
upon the two
LORD,
one lot for the
lot for
other
and the
scapegoat.
the
goat I killed.
first
The
in
blood
I took its
and carried it
basin
a
man could
ordinary
where no
follow
the veil,
through
the thick dark,
into
it before
sprinkled
and I
seat:
mercy
the
shall he kill the
Then
of the sin offering,
goat
people,
that is for the
his blood within
bring
and
vail.
the
goat I
second
But the
not kill.
did
both my hands
laid
I
head,
living
upon its
over it
confessed
and I
mouth
own
out of my
of all
wrong
all the
people,
the
it upon the
laid
and
creature:
shall lay both
Aaron
And
head
his hands upon the
goat,
live
of the
over him
confess
and
the iniquities of the
all
of Israel,
children
their transgressions
all
and
their sins,
all
in
them upon the head
putting
goat,
of the
him away
send
and shall
of a
hand
by the
man
fit
the wilderness.
into
I stood at
then
And
camp
the edge of the
it go,
watched
and
and smaller,
smaller
it all away into
carrying
where no one
land
a
it:
find
would ever
shall bear
goat
And the
him
upon
their iniquities
all
land
unto a
inhabited.
not
that
thing
Here is the
let me rest.
never
sin offering
one
It was
goats.
yet it took two
of Moses said
law
The
plainly:
it
take of
shall
And he
of the children
congregation
the
two kids of
Israel
of
for a sin
goats
the
offering.
killed;
One I
away
sent
the other I
alive.
myself,
And I asked
upon year:
year
two?
why
to
both
Why not put
death?
died to pay;
One
to carry
lived
the other
off
it
meant to
God
as though
at once
things
show two
creature could
single
that no
hold.
it faithfully,
performed
I
of it
riddle
and the
me home.
followed
honest
And I will be
you,
with
man must
honest
for an
before God.
honest
be
obeyed,
I
and
believed.
I
went home clean
people
The
Himself had
LORD
for the
day
said that on that
from
clean
they would be
sins before Him.
their
all
was real.
cleansing
That
never
And yet it was
end.
the
the people sinned
year
Every
afresh,
I came
year
and every
whole
back and did the
again.
thing
you must make
cleansing
A
every year is true,
again
finished;
but it is not
returned with each
need
the
year,
new
as the feast.
faithful
as
age
old
And in my
pressed on
fear
a quiet
me,
one
not speak aloud
dared
I
altar:
at the
the blood
all
that for
out,
poured
I
ever pointing
only
I was
at some greater atonement
pointing
hands could
own
that my
reach.
never
sign.
I was a
know
I did not yet
what.
of
the
see
I did not
in my own day.
answer
you now looking
tell
I
side
far
back from the
by the
life
of my
after
long
light that came
down my office
laid
I
of Atonement
Day
what every
reaching toward.
always
was
word
later
That
Hebrews
the letter to the
what I had
plainly
says
feared:
only
I carried
blood
that the
never finish it.
could
is a remembrance again
there
of sins
made
year.
every
possible
For it is not
of bulls
blood
that the
should take
goats
and of
sins.
away
shadow
It was a
waits for
shadow
and a
it.
casts
the body that
came.
body
The
a Man,
came
There
Jesus,
blood
own
and with His
basin
He did what my
pictured:
only
of blood
once,
entered
He
finished.
and it was
letter says of
same
That
Him:
by the blood of
Neither
and calves,
goats
blood
but by his own
in once into
entered
he
place,
holy
the
obtained eternal redemption for
having
us.
blood He
own
By His
the price
paid
in His own death
bearing
our sin had
judgment
the
earned
One
and He was the
the guilt was
whom
upon
away,
clean
laid and carried
the
laid
as I had
on the goat
sin
people's
into the wild.
sent
I
Isaiah,
after
came
the prophet who
me,
it:
wrote
hath laid
LORD
and the
of
iniquity
on him the
all.
us
were
there
That is why
two.
creature could show
single
No
halves at once the
both
guilt
price paid and the
off
carried
were finished in
both
and
Priest.
one
Him outside the
led
They
to die
city
without the
taken
His body
gate,
offering's body
sin
as the
outside the camp
carried
was
burned.
and
says:
The letter
Jesus also,
Wherefore
the
sanctify
that he might
people
blood,
with his own
the gate.
without
suffered
one
And He did the
I never could.
thing
stood at my
always
I
work;
behind
chair
there was no
veil.
that
it,
finished
But this Priest
down:
and sat
man,
But this
he had offered one
after
for ever,
sins
sacrifice for
right
sat down on the
of God.
hand
I trembled
veil
And the
before
that shut every
curtain
the
but one out,
man
a year
day
one
hour
very
was torn the
died,
He
hand.
human
by no
Matthew,
gospel,
in his
it:
records
And,
behold,
of the temple
veil
the
in twain
rent
was
to the
top
from the
bottom.
me
hear
So
moment,
and be still a
thing
for this is the
my whole life
waited
I
understand.
to
not come to me.
Do
to a
come
Do not
goat,
altar,
yearly
or a
linen
or a priest in
a dying
himself
who is
and must wash before
man
draw near.
dares
he
of it ever stayed
None
done.
can.
He
the High
Jesus
Come to
who finished it.
Priest
to
come
If you will
Him,
is not held
sin
your
for another year
down
away,
carried
it is
not inhabited,
land
into a
as the east
far
as
west,
is from the
to be counted against
never
again.
you
sang in his
David
So
psalm,
before:
long
as the east
far
As
west,
is from the
removed
so far hath he
from us.
transgressions
our
I trembled before
veil
The
torn,
is
will ever
hand
and no
it shut again.
sew
in is thrown
way
The
open
wide
one
not for one man
a year,
day
you.
but for
letter says:
same
That
therefore,
Having
brethren,
to enter into the
boldness
holiest
of Jesus.
blood
by the
a
need
You do not
like me to go
priest
longer.
in for you any
you the
ask
So I
I asked myself behind
question
veil,
that
year,
every
in my
heart
with my
throat
there is no
now
only
left in it:
fear
in?
come
will you
clean
Not when you are
enough,
year,
not next
blood
own
not by your
now,
but
His.
on
Come.
who finished
One
Trust the
ever foreshadowed.
only
what I
in
Walk
is open,
holiest
the
is already inside.
Jesus
and